Daniel Wallace

Software Development Computer Arts Creative Design

545 SE 27th Ave Portland, OR 97214 971.322.5162

WallaceDaniel.com github.com/wallacedaniel linkedin.com/in/daniel-wallace-dev

Languages and Tools
C# ASP.NET MVC Visual Studio

C# ASP.NET MVC Visual Studio Python SQLite Tkinter Beautiful Soup JavaScript jQuery Knockout JS HTML CSS Bootstrap SQL in MicroSoft SQL Server Git

WordPress, WooCommerce Maya, Photoshop, AfterEffects, Illustrator

Additional Skills

Strong visual, graphic, and compositional skills. 7 years past experience in theater, film and television production.

Portland based creative working in software development with education in media arts and animation. Focused on full stack development with an eye for clean front end design.

Project Experience

Prosper IT Consulting / Software Development Intern PortlandTech.org Job Board ASP.NET MVC Application

MARCH 2017 - PRESENT, PORTLAND, OREGON

ASP.NET MVC5 project in Visual Studio. Included Identity Framework for managing user accounts registration. Worked code first, using Entity Framework 6 and developed a method to seed the database with JSON data. Team Foundation Server troubleshooting. Used Python 3.6 with Beautiful Soup to scrape target sites as JSON.

ZD Design/ WordPress Development

SEPTEMBER 2013 - APRIL 2014, PORTLAND, OREGON

Informal internship through Patchworks Media. Aided in the development of several small business Wordpress sites. Focused on HTML, CSS, PHP editing, and Wordpress/ Woocommerce development.

Education

The Tech Academy/ Software Development Bootcamp NOVEMBER 2016 - APRIL 2017, PORTLAND, OREGON

15 Week Software Development Bootcamp focused on C# ASP.NET development in Visual Studio. Courses in Python, database with MicroSoft SQL Server, and web technologies including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and Bootstrap. Also provided technology foundations, development industry introduction, version control, and project management coursework, culminating in a two week partnered live project.

Art Institute / Media Arts & Animation

SEPTEMBER 2010 - MAY 2011, PORTLAND, OREGON

3D animation and process, 3D modeling, video and image editing, and art foundations.

Academy of Art/ Media Arts & Animation

SEPTEMBER 2007 - MAY 2009, PORTLAND, OREGON

Online courses in 3d art and animation, software, storyboarding, and art foundations.